# **ABOUT ME**

computing start the computer of computing enal	I'm happily married to a fantastic wife and have two wonderful children. My into ted as a child when I was captivated by being able to type in BASIC code and do as I wanted. My fascination has never dwindled and I'm still amazed bles the what was previously thought of as impossible. I've spent the majority for the NHS as I value being able to make others' lives better.	d make at how
	I regularly work with Git, AWS, Docker, Docker-Compose, HTML, P, Cordova, T-SQL and IIS. I also have experience with Azure, C#, ASP.net, I	
the latest techn	I have a keen interest in DevOps and Cloud. I can regularly be found tinkering that has peaked my curiosity. I enjoy spending time with my family, cars an attempt to stay healthy I like to walk and cycle.	_

#### **Awards**

• Outstanding Teamwork Award - Non Clinical (Runner Up) Staff Awards Jun 2019

Mensa

HackFest (2<sup>nd</sup> Place) Digital Health Rewired Mar 2019

Organisation membership • British Computer Society

- HackFest (3<sup>rd</sup> Place) Digital Health Summer School Jul 2018
- Chairman's Innovation Award (Winner) Staff Awards May 2018
- Enhancing Care by Sharing Data and Information (Shortlisted) HSJ Awards Nov 2016
- Part-time Continuing Scholarship University of Westminster Sep 2008

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner AWS Training and Certification Feb 2021
- AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials AWS Training and Certification Feb 2021
- AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials Day AWS Sep 2020
- Beauty Therapist Diploma Distinction Centre of Excellence Aug 2020
- Foundation Certificate in Business Analysis British Computer Society Jun 2019
- Safer Design and Implementation NHS Digital Jun 2018
- NEWS2 National Early Warning Score Feb 2018
- Clinical Risk Management NHS Digital Mar 2017
- Leadership Foundations NHS Leadership Academy Sep 2014
- Developing Web Applications using Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 Microsoft Oct 2010
- BCS Level 1 Award in IT User Skills British Computer Society Nov 2009
- ECDL Approved Centre Staff Training Programme British Computer Society Dec 2008
- PRINCE II Foundation APM Group Ltd Oct 2008
- European Computer Driving Licence (ECDL) Expert British Computer Society Aug
   2008
  - Advanced Word Processing (Microsoft Word)
     Advanced Spreadsheets (Microsoft Excel)
     Advanced Presentation (Microsoft PowerPoint)
- **ELITE** British Computer Society *May 2008*
- NHS Health British Computer Society Apr 2008
- NHS Essentials IT Skills Approved Centre Staff Training Programme British Computer Society Mar 2008
- MSC Training Course Metroploitain Police Mar 2007
  - Public Order Act
     Criminal Attempts Act
     Human Rights Act
     Police & Criminal Evidence Act
     Stopping Vehicles & Speaking to Drivers
     Breach of the Peace
     Traffic Incidents
     Going Equipped to Steal
     Process by Summons
     Criminal Damage
     Drunkenness
     Assaults
     Domestic Violence
     Evidence
     Actions Book
     Offensive Weapons
     Articles with Points & Blades
     Policing Safely
     Penalty Notices for Disorder
     Hate Crime
     Theft
     Property Lost & Found
     Pocket Book Rules
     Investigation
     Rights, Fairness & Responsibilities
     Stop & Search
     Stop & Account
     Discretion
     Arrest Powers
     Arrest Procedure & Initial Detention
     Detention, Questioning & Treatment
     Metropolitan Police District
     Personal Radios
     Self-defined Ethnicity

- BCS Level 2 Certificate for IT Users British Computer Society Mar 2007
- Certificate in Training Delivery Skills The Training Foundation Jan 2007
  - Assessment of Strengths
     The Self-fulfilling Prophecy & Body Language
     Using Questions in Training
     Writing Learning Objectives
     Preparing your Training
     Session
     Using Visual Aids
     The Skills Development Cycle
     Project
- European Computer Driving Licence (ECDL) British Computer Society May 2005
  - Basic Concepts of Information Technology
     Using the Computer & Managing Files
     Word Processing (Microsoft Word)
     Spreadsheets (Microsoft Excel)
     Database (Microsoft Access)
     Presentation (Microsoft PowerPoint)
     Information & Communication
     Using IT

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

**Application Development Manager** The Hillingdon Hospitals NHS FT May 2018 - Present

I am responsible for managing in-house application developments, ranging from minor enhancements to existing applications, to the creation of new, fully featured, applications. Managing, and developing as part of a team of full-stack developers I am required to have an in-depth knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, APIs and T-SQL. Products we use include VSCode, Chrome, IIS, Windows Server, SSMS, Cordova, GitHub, and AWS. My role requires me to be able to create applications from the first line of code to their production deployment and on-going support. The position includes line management responsibility for two Developers.

Senior Application Developer The Hillingdon Hospitals NHS FT May 2015 - Apr 2018

As above, with the exception of management resposponsibilities. The position included line management responsibility for one Junior Developer.

**Senior Information Analyst** The Hillingdon Hospitals NHS FT Feb 2010 - Apr 2015

I was responsible for the timely and accurate completion of statutory returns and submission of

mandated datasets to various external bodies in various formats, including the XML NHS standard. This required me to keep abreast of, and interpret, current information standards, reporting requirements and information policy. I also had responsibility for the design and ongoing development of the trust's in-house management information data warehouse and web-based reporting system (T-SQL and C# ASP.net). This involved data manipulation from a variety of sources, data validation and the writing of views, functions and stored procedures. When required, I was responsible for compiling data for Freedom of Information requests and other ad-hoc data requests. The position included line management responsibility for one Information Analyst.

I was responsible for developing and delivering in-house training programmes and training guides to meet the needs of individuals and groups of Trust staff. This involved delivering training across a spectrum of skill levels and mixed ability groups. I was also accountable for managing the ECDL programme in accordance with the British Computer Society regulations. This included ensuring that candidates were fully registered with the British Computer Society, all aspects of training, administration, invigilation of examinations and the recording of full and accurate data. I was also involved in the project planning of training for the implementation of new systems, both clinical and non-clinical, across the Trust. I was given the role of lead trainer for three systems.

Special Constable (Volunteer) Metropolitan Police Mar 2007 - Jan 2010

As a Special Constable for the Metropolitan Police I had the same duties, powers and responsibilities as a regular Constable. I made arrests and followed them through the booking-in, interview, charging and releasing processes. I was also involved with drug raids, burglary investigations and anti-terrorism Stop & Searches.

## **EDUCATION**

BSc (Hons) Computer Science - First Class University of Westminster Sep 2005 - Jun 2009

• Perspectives of Computer Science • Introduction to Computer Programming I • ICT Tools & Systems • Database Introduction • Information Fundamentals • Introduction to Computer Programming II • Database Theory & Practise • Computer Organisation & System Software • Systems Analysis • Rapid Applications Development I • Database Systems Development • Digital Media Tools • Rapid Applications Development II • Comparative Information Systems Methodologies • Business Enabling Systems • Network Operations • Project Management I • E-Commerce & Intranet Systems • Project Management II • E-Commerce Systems Implementation • Project I • Internet Server Solutions • Computer Security • Project II

A-Levels Watford Grammar School for Boys Sep 2000 - Jul 2003

• Physics - B • Mathematics - C • Chemistry - E • AS Geography - E

GCSEs Watford Grammar School for Boys Sep 1998 - Jul 2000

Mathematics - A\* • Physics - A\* • German - A\* • Chemistry - A • English Language - A
 English Literature - A
 French - A
 Biology - B
 Geography - B

#### **PROJECTS**

**Hillingdon Care Record** Electronic Patient Record with 1,200 distinct users and over 200,000 transactions per month. The app combines data feeds from multiple clinical systems to produce a first point of contact with the patient record

hObs Patient Obserations app with 1,000 distinct users and over 500,000 transactions per month. The app allows for the recording of patient observations and assists in calculating the NEWS2 score. Other observations are included in the app such as Sepsis, End of Life and Pain Management
<b>qMan</b> Queue management app that allows pateints to check-in and prints tickets, and staff to manage waits and call patients in to clinic rooms
eVetting Referral vetting app that allows various referral documents to be electronically collated and progressed through a vetting process. Decisions are audit trailed and made available to other apps
RISView A viewer app for the archived data of a now retired radiology application. Implemented to avoid contract charges while maintaining access to the data
EnCrypt Morturary management app that allows for tracking of patients through the mortuary process
ED Waits Infomation screen for use in the Emergency Department. Its purpose is to inform patients of current live waiting times and provide relevant innformation to their attendance
SMS Messaging Reminder and survey text messaging based on extracts from other systems that are not able to natively support SMS messaging
<b>DocConvert</b> Document conversion API that converts various document types to web-friendly alternatives
COVID-19 Suite A series of, quickly delivered, smaller apps that supported the NHS in dealing

with the COVID-19 pandemic

- **Absence Monitoring** Efficient tracking of high numbers of staff calling in sick
- Antibody Test Requesting Allowing staff to register and request a test
- Antibody Test Booking Allow staff prioritised for testing to book a test
- **Swab Test Monitoring** Record swab testing and compliance against requirements
- **FITMask Testing** Record PPE testing and compliance against requirements
- **VacTrac** Allow staff to book vaccinations and track performance

- Public Facing Vaccine Bookings & Management app Allow local NHS staff to book vaccinations
- Public Facing Phelbotomy Bookings Pre-booking service for a previously walk-in service
- FITMask Service Bookings Diary management for PPE testing team